A Guide to the Papers of the Libertarian Party, 1979-1983
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Libertarian Party 1979-1983
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10187-w
This collection contains ca. 5200 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of David P. Bergland, of Costa Mesa, California, on February 6, 1985.
Scope and Content Information
The papers consist chiefly of financial material pertaining to the 1980 presidential candidacy of Ed Clark, and contain accounts paid and payable; reports of receipts and expenditures made to the Federal Election Commission; campaign expenditure files; correspondence and credit invoices of the Finance Committee; and files re fundraising material and contributions.
There are also general campaign files; publicity material; internal memoranda; media files; statements of Ed Clark; and newsclippings re Clark and the campaign.
Contents List
- Topical
  - Accounts Paid 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Accounts Paid: Avis Telecommunications 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  - Accounts Paid: Edward E. Clark 1980 (Box 1)
  - Accounts Paid: Federal Express 1980-1983 (Box 1)
  - Accounts Paid: Webcraft 1980-1983 (Box 1)
  - Accounts Payable: A-B 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  - Accounts Payable: C-L 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  - Accounts Payable: M-Z 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  - Accounts Payable: Casio-Wolf, Inc. 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Accounts Payable: David Koch 1980 (Box 2)
  - Advertising 1980-1982 (Box 2)
  - Biographical Sketches 1980 (Box 2)
  - Briefings and News Releases 1980 (Box 2)
  - Campaign 1979-1980, n.d., 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Campaign Brochure 1980 (Box 2)
  - Campaign Notebook 1980 (Box 2)
  - Campaign: Clark Brochure Materials 1980 (Box 2)
  - "Clark for President: A Report on the 1980 Libertarian Presidential Campaign" 1980 (Box 2)
  - "Clark on the Issues" [1980] (Box 3)
  - Contributions 1980 (Box 3)
  - Contributions: Political Action Committees 1978-1980 (Box 3)
  - Debates 1980 (Box 3)
  - Federal Election Commission: Contribution Report 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Federal Election Commission: Deposits 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Federal Election Commission: Miscellaneous 1977-1981 (Box 3)
  - Federal Election Commission: Report of Receipts and Expenditures 1979 (Box 3)
  - Federal Election Commission: Report of Receipts and Expenditures 1980 Jan-Apr (Box 3)
  - Federal Election Commission: Report of Receipts and Expenditures 1980 May - Dec, 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Federal Election Commission: Report of Receipts and Expenditures 1981 (Box 4)
  - Federal Election Commission: Report of Receipts and Expenditures Discrepancies 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Federal Election Commission: Daniel Paul Wiener 1979 (Box 4)
  - Finance: Campaign Expenditures 1980 (Box 4)
  - Finance: Campaign Expenditures 1980, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Finance Committee: Correspondence 1980 (Box 5)
  - Finance Committee: Correspondence--Internal 1980, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Finance Committee: Credit Invoices 1979-1980, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Fundraising 1980 (Box 6)
  - Fundraising: Names in the News 1982 (Box 6)
  - Fundraising: States 1980, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - "How to Accurately Choose a Politician" 1980 (Box 6)
  - Internal Memoranda 1980, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Invitations to Campaign Social Events 1980 (Box 6)
  - Labor Statistics 1980 (Box 6)
  - Libertarian Party Tenth Anniversary 1980 (Box 7)
  - Media 1980 (Box 7)
  - Media: Television--ABC 1980 (Box 7)
  - Media: Television--CBS 1980 (Box 7)
  - Media: Television--NBC 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - National Headquarters Functions [1980] (Box 7)
  - Opinion Research 1980 (Box 7)
  - Scheduling 1980 (Box 7)
  - Staff Meetings 1980 (Box 7)
  - Statements: General 1980 (Box 7)
  - Statements of Ed Clark 1980 Jan - May (Box 7)
  - Statements of Ed Clark 1980 June - Nov, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Steering Committee 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Volunteers [1980] (Box 8)
  - White Papers [1980] (Box 8)
- Printed -- Newspaper Clippings
  - Printed Material 1979, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Printed Material 1980 Jan - June, 8 folders (Box 9)
  - Printed Material 1980 June - Sep, 7 folders (Box 10)
  - Printed Material 1980 Sep - Oct, 8 folders (Box 11)
  - Printed Material 1980 Oct, 6 folders (Box 12)
  - Printed Material 1980 Nov - Dec, 5 folders (Box 13)
  - Printed Material 1981 Jan - Feb, 2 folders (Box 13)